A Guide to the Monticello Music Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Monticello Music Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Multiple numbers
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must use microfilm of these manuscripts unless permission to use originals has been granted by senior Special Collections staff.
Acquisition Information
#3177-a was deposited by the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation, 1949 September 12. A 1723 .J4 no.1-95 was purchased for the Tracy W. McGregor Library. #7443-f was deposited by the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation, 1971 February 12 and returned to the Foundation 1986 May 13.
Biographical/Historical: Appendix II, Revised by Emily Gale and Matt Jones:
In the revision of this appendix, we have maintained the integrity of Helen Cripe's original document, organizing it as she did, by the present manner in which it is stored. We have added information that seemed to be of potential interest to future researchers and others with an interest in the collection, making every effort to be consistent and to clearly reflect what one finds when looking at the collection. We have added information from the title pages of complete collections of printed sheet music, which are indicated in italics, and have included information about publication when it was available. Some of this detective work was done by Cripe and is not available simply from looking at the collection. In these cases, that information is stated in square brackets. Titles of individual songs are stated in quotation marks. Inconsistency in capitalization and spelling within these titles reflects what is printed on the actual documents. We have also added some description of the music when that information was not necessarily clear from the title.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of music owned by Thomas Jefferson, Martha Jefferson Randolph and her children and grandchildren.
Contents List
- Part I: Monticello Music Collection, 6 boxes
  3177
  - Hardbound book. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Inscribed on inside of front cover: Thomas Jefferson. Monticello. Albemarle Co. Virginia. This book given by T.J. to his grand daughter Virginia Jefferson Randolph. Handwritten notation about tuning the harpsichord, German Flute, and string instruments on reverse of title page. This book contains about 110 short minuets, some with names and some without. Those named are generally named after a person, or simply after the composer. The First Collection of Volume the 2nd of the Most Favourite Minuets with their Basses Which are Now in Vogue and Perform'd at all Publick Assemblies and Entertainments, Neatly Fitted for the German Flute, Violin, or Harpsichord. Printed and sold by David Rutherford at the Violin and German Flute in St. Martins Court near Leicester Fields, [London, ca. 1753]. Price: 6 dollars.
  - Softbound book., Marble paper, with envelope of page fragments. Inscribed on inside of front cover: "This book supposed to belong to Martha Jefferson (Wife of Thomas Jefferson) who was Martha Wayles." (Box-folder 1:2)
    Manuscript music book containing a mixture of songs and hymns (some with text), excerpts from Corelli violin solos, Handel keyboard works, themes and variations, various works for pianoforte (some attributed, others anonymous), scales and preludes in all of the major and minor keys. Several hands are represented, and some of the writing has been identified as that of Martha Wayles Jefferson.
  - Hardbound music book with several individual pieces of music bound into one volume., Inscribed: "Mademoiselle Jefferson Panthemont Paris" on cover page of Stabat Mater. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Contains:
    Stabat Mater, composed by Sigr. [Giovanni Battista] Pergolesi. Musical score for two treble instruments, bass, and continuo with figures and choir. Latin text.
    An Ode by Mr. Pop, Adapted to the Principal Airs of the Hymn Stabat Mater Composed by Signor Pergolesi. An Ode Entitled 'The Dying Christian to his Soul' by Alex: Pop Esq. Adapted to the Stabat Mater of Sig. Pergolesi. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand [London, ca. 1764]. Score for two violins, viola, bbass, and choir. English text.
    The Anthem Which Was Performed in Westminster Abbey at the Funeral of Her most Sacred Majesty, Queen Caroline. Composed by Mr. [Georg Friedrich] Handel. Vol. II. Printed for William Randall Successor to the late Mr. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand [London, ca. 1770]. Score for two violins, viola, bass, two oboes, and choir. English text.
    Handel's Celebrated Coronation Anthems in Score, for Voices and Instruments. Vol. I. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand [London, 1743]. Score for 3 Tromba, Tympano, 2 oboes, 2 bassoons, 3 violins, viola, cello, bass, choir, 2 soloists, and organ. English text.
  - String bound music book. (Box-folder 1:4)
    The Psalms Set Full for the Organ or Harpsichord as they are laid in Churches and Chappels in the manner given out as also with their Interludes of great Variety by Mr. Dan Purcell, late Organist of St. Andrew's Halbrown. Price: 6 dollars. Printed for I Walsh Servant in Ordinary to his Majesty at the Harp and Hautboy in Ka...Street in the Strand and IH are at the Viol and Flute in Cornhill near the Royal Exchange [London, n.d.]. Several have the words written in, possibly in Martha Randolph's handwriting. Includes:
    Canterbury Tune
    York Tune
    Southwell Tune
    St. Mary's Tune
    100th Psalm Tune
    Windsor Tune
    London Tune
    St. David's Tune [one of TJ's favorites]
    119th Psalm Tune
    148th Psalm Tune
    113th Psalm Tune
  - Songs and Duets Composed by Mrs. Cosway., Inscribed: "Thomas Jefferson from Mrs. Cosway" on cover page. Eight pages of short songs and duets in Italian, with harp and pianoforte accompaniment. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Seven Songs for the harpsichord or Forte Piano The Words and Music Composed by Francis Hopkinson. Published and sold by T. Dobson, Philadelphia [1788] [ca. 1784]. Hopkinson dedicated these songs to George Washington. He sent Washington and Jefferson each a copy of them in December, 1788. Original title page is missing from sheet music, but a photocopy of the version at the Library of Congress indicates title, composer, and publication information. Songs with pianoforte accompaniment and texted verses. Despite the title on the cover page, there are actually eight songs in this collection.
  - Hardbound volume of several collections, missing front cover. (Box-folder 1:6)
    The Harpsichord or Spinnet Miscellany Being a Gradation of Proper Lessons from the Beginner to the tolerable Performer Chiefly intended to save Masters the trouble of writing for their Pupils to which are prefixed some Rules for Time by Robert Bremner. Printed and Sold as his Music Shop on the Harp and Hautboy...[London, ca. 1765]. Keyboard lesson book with exercises.
    Eight Lessons for the Harpsichord, Composed by the Celebrated Giovanni Battista Pergolessi, Author of the Stabat Mater. Printed and sold by Longman Lukey and Co. No. 26 Cheapside where may be had lately published justs [?] Lessons. [London, ca. 1771]. Price: 7s, 6d. Printed score of eight keyboard sonatas.
    Variations for the Harpsichord to a Minuet of Corelli's, the Gavot in Otho [by Handell], and the Old Highland Laddie, by J. Snow late organist of St. John's College Oxon. Printed for J. Longman & Co. at the Harp and Crown, No. 26 Cheapside, where may be had lately published the harpside [London, ca. 1769]. Price: 2s.
    Six Favorite Overtures Adapted for the Harpsichord for Organ, Composed by C[hristian] F[erdinand] Abel. Engraved, printed, & Sold by Longman, Lukey, & Co. No. 26 Cheapside, where may be had just puslish'd for the harpsichord or organ [London, ca. 1769-75]. Price: 4s.
    Six Sonatas for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord. Composed by Sigr. C. E. [Carl Philip Emanuel] Bach. Printed and Sold by Longman Luckey & Co., No. 26 Cheapside, London [ca. 1775]. Price: 8s.
  - Bound volume of printed music, with green hardcover. (Box-folder 2:7)
    Six Concerto, pour le Clavecin ou le Forte-Piano avec Accompagnement de deux Violons et Basse Dédiés á Madame La Duchesse de lancastre, composes par j. S. Schroetter, Oeuver III. Printed Chez Mr. Boyer au Magazin de Musique, Rude e Richelieu á la Clef d'Or, Passage du Café de foy. Chez Madame Le Menu Rue de Roule á la Clef d'Or. [Paris, ca. 1785]. Prix: 12t. Inscribed on title page: Mademoiselle Jefferson, 'Panthemont' Paris, 1785.
    Ouverture et Airs de Ballets D'Alexandre aux Indies, arranges pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano par l'auteur avec un Violon ad libitum Dédiés á Madame La Contesse Charles de Peysac [by de Mereau]. Chez des Lauriers Md. De Papier rue St Honore á côté de celle des prouvairea, Paris [ca. 1765]. Contains dedication page to Mme. La Contesse Charles de Peysac by de Mereau.
  - Bound volume of manuscript music, with green hardcover., Inscribed MJ on front cover, and entitled Sonatas Pour le Clavecin par differens auteurs 1788. Inscribed on inside of front cover: "Mademoiselle Jefferson, Panthemont, Paris" (Box-folder 2:8)
    Pasquali's method of tuning the harpsichord
    Sonata by Ferdinand Stoes
    Rondeau
    Sonata by Ernest Eixner [Eichnerl
    The Merman's Song by Haydn
    That Overture from Alexandre Aux Indies [by de Mereaux]
    Two double-sided sheets tucked inside this volume:
    Mary's Dream of (?) Sandy's Ghost
    Tis Not the Bloom on Damon's Cheek
    Overture de Blaise et Babet arrangé par Mr. X
  - String bound, printed and handwritten sheet music. (Box-folder 2:8a)
    Song in Alexander's Feast by Mr. Handel. Song for voice and pianoforte with English text. From Lady's Magazine for October, 1790.
    Thou Soft Flowing Avon Song for voice and pianoforte accompaniment with English text.
    Air - Lison Dormoit. Song for voice and pianoforte accompaniment with vocable text.
    Lochaber. For solo keyboard.
    Aria with Variations by AK. For solo keyboard.
    Song and (?) Iris, by Haydn. For solo keyboard.
  - Four double-sided loose sheets. Song melodies with text. (Box-folder 2:8b)
    Includes:
    Black Eyed Susan, in eight verses
    Two versions of Catch
    War Song altered from Moore, three verses
    My Nanie O three verses
    Dulce Domum, two verses
    Oh Breathe Not his Name, two verses
  - One handwritten sheet for solo keyboard instrument. (Box-folder 2:8c)
    Danza El [?]
  - One double-sided handwritten sheet for solo keyboard instrument. (Box-folder 2:8d)
    Duke of York's March
    Choeur des Voyageurs
  - Collection of loose sheets for solo keyboard instrument. (Box-folder 2:8e)
    Air de Danse de Roland
    Musette D'armide
    Menuet del Sigr. Slogneb
    Duo de Blaise et Babet
    Sonate del Sigr. Haydn
  - Three double-sided handwritten sheets. (Box-folder 2:8f)
    Partial unidentified keyboard part
    Air for solo keyboard
    The Shipwrecked Seaman's Ghost, song with English text
    The Mermaid's Song attributed to Haydn, song with English text
  - Bound volume, with green hardcover., Inscribed: "Mademoiselle Jefferson abbaye Royale de Panthemont Paris 1785," on the front. (Box-folder 2:9)
    Quatre Sonates pour la Harpe ou le Clavecin et Piano-Forte avec accompagnement de Violon Par M. [Valentino] Nicolai, Oeuvre 1 Gravé par Le Roy. Published Chez Cousineau Luthier Bréveté de la Reine et de Madame la Comtesse d'Artois, rue des Poulies. Sheet music for solo keyboard instrument. Price: 7tt.
    Trois Sonates Pour le Clavecin ou le Piano-Forte avec Accompagnement de Violon dediées á Messieurs Montagu Burgoyne par Valantino Nicolai, Op: VII. Published Chez le Duc, Rue Traversiere St. Honoré, au Magazin de Musique. Price: 6tt.
    Trois Duos Concertants pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano et Violon Obligé Composé par M. Nicolai, Oeuvre Xm. Published Chez le Sr. Sieber Musicien rue St. Honoré entre celles des Vielles Etave et celle Dorleans chez l'Apothicaire, No. 92. Price: 7tt. Sheet music for solo keyboard instrument.
    All of these are typical of the many selections published in arrangements for solo instrument and thoroughbass. The keyboard instrument played the thoroughbass and any instrument could be used for the solo -- usually the violin or flute was used. These selections by Nicolai were published in France, ca. 1780-83.
  - Bound volume, with green hardcover., Inscribed: "Mademoiselle De Jefferson 1785" on front cover. (Box-folder 2:10)
    Sei Sonate di Cembalo e Violino Obligato Dedicate a Madama Brillon de Jouy da Luigi Boccherini Di Lucca, Gravee par Mme. La V. Leclair. Opera V. Published Chez M. Venier Editeur de plusieurs Ouvrages de Musique, Rue Traversiere vis-á-vis l'Hotel de Richelieu, Paris [ca. 1780]. Price: 9tt.
    Six Sonates pour le Clavecin avec Accompagnement d'un Violon ad Libitum Dédiées á Mademoiselle de Chastel, par Mr. [Johann Friedrich] Edelmann, Oeuvre I. Published Chez M. R [?] Magasin de Musique rue de Richelieu a la Clef d'Or Passage du Caffé de foy, Paris [ca. 1780]. Price: 9tt.
    Trois Sonates en Trio pour le Clavecin ou le Fortepiano avec accompagnement d'un Violon et Violoncelle ad libitum. Dediées á Mr. De Fontenet Conseiller de Regenee, Secretaire du Cabinet et des Commendements et Surintendant de la Musique de S.A.S. Monseigneur le Due Regnant des deux Ponta par Ernesto Eichner, Oeuvre 11. Published Chez Mme. Berault Mde. De Musique, rue de la Comedie fran?oise á coté de Mr. Guersant Lutier, Paris [ca. 1780]. Price: 7tt.
  - Leather bound volume: (Box-folder 3:11)
    XII Solos for a Violin with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsichord or Violon Cello Composed by Arcangelo Correli: These solos are Printed from a curious Edition Publish'd at Rome by the Author, Op. 5. Printed and Sold by I. Walsh in Catherine Street in Strand of whom may be had all the Works of Corelli (viz) his Sonatas and Concertos in Parts and in Score [London, ca. 1740]. Inscribed: "Thomas Jefferson, Monticello."
    The Second Part Containing Preludes, Allemands, Corants, Jiggs, Sarabands, Gavots, and Follia by Arcangelo Corelli. Printed for J. Walsh.
    XII Solos for a Violin with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsichord or Bass Violin, Composed by Antonio Vivaldi, Op. 2. Printed for & sold by I. Walsh Servant to his Majesty at the Harp and Hoboy in Catherine Street in the Strand [London, ca. 1721].
    XII Solos for a German Flute, or Hoboy or a Violin with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsichord or Bass Violin, composed by Carlo Tessarini di Rimini, Op. 2. Note: where they are sold may be had 12 Concertos for Violins in 6 Parts by the same Author, also great variety of Music for the German Flute. Printed for and Sold by I. Walsh Music Printer & Instrument maker to his Majesty at the Harp & Hoboy in Catherine Street in the Strand [London, ca. 1736].
    Six Solos for a Violin and Bass, Composed by Wenceslaus Wodizka First Violin to the Elector of Bavaria. Printed for J: Johnson facing Bow Church in Cheapside [London, ca. 1750].
    Six Favorite Solos for a Violin with a Bass for the Violincello and Harpsichord, Composed by Sigr.[Carlo Antonio] Campioni and Sigr. Chabran. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand [London, ca. 1760]. Price: 5s.
  - Bound volume, with cover missing. (Box-folder 3:12)
    Overture to Artaxerxes, by T. A. Arne. Printed and Sold by J. Bland at his Music Warehouse No. 45 Holborn [London, ca. 1790]. Price: 6 dollars.
    Haydn's Celebrated Overture Adapted for the Harpsichord or Pianoforte. Printed and Sold by H. Andrews at the Musical Circulating Library No. 129 New Bond Street, London. Price 2.
    Two Grand Sonatas, for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord, with an Accompaniment for the Violin ad Libitum Composed by Ignace Pleyel, Op. 7 or 11. Printed and Sold by J. Bland at his Music Warehouse, 45 Holborn where may be had the greatest Variety of Music. English or Foreign and all this Author's works [London, ca. 1790]. Price: 4s.
    Three Sonatas for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord Selected from The Six Dedicated to the Baroness von Dieden Composed by E[rnesto] Eichner. Printed & Sold by J. bland at his Music Warehouse, 45 Holborn. [London, ca. 1790]. Price: 4s. Inscribed: "Martha Jefferson, Paris 1786."
    The following are six issues of Bland's Collection of Sonatas, Lessons, Overtures, Capricios, Divertimentos, &c, &c for the harpsichord or pianoforte without accompaniment, by the Most Esteemed Composers. This series was published in London, ca. 1790-94.
    No. 20, Vol 2: Edelman's Sonata I, Op. 1, Vento -- Sonata
    No. 22, Vol 2: Edelman's Sonata I, Op. 16, Overture to The Bastile, Edelman's Sonata II, Op. 16
    No. 28, Vol 3: Pleyel's Cottage Maid With Variations for the Piano Forte by T. A. Geary.Edelman's Sonata III, Op. 8
    No. 29, Vol 3: Edelman's Sonata III, Op. 16, Martini's Grand Overture to Henry the Fourth
    No. 38, Vol. 4: Gluck's Overture -- Paradie ed Elena, Edelman's Sonata IV, Op. 16
    No. 42, Vol 4: Overture Oedipe á Colonne, Arranged by Lachnitth, Eichner's Sonata IV
    Haydn's Grand Orchestra Sinfonie, adapted for Piano Forte or Harpsichord. With an Accompaniment for Violin by Rimbault, Printed and sold by H. Write, Catherine Street, Strand. [London, ca. 1785]. Price: 3s. No. 4. Haydn's Grand Orchestra Symphonies as Performed at the Nobility's Concerts; Adapted for Organ, Harpsichord, or Piano Forte. Strains that might create a Soul Under the ribs of Death-Milton. Printed for J. Bland at his Music Warehouse. No. 45 Holborn where may be had by the above Composer, the greatest Variety of Sinfonies, Quartetts, Trios, & Harpsichord Sonatas with every new Musical Publication both English and Foreign [London, ca. 1785]. Price: 2.
    Concerto, pour le Clavecin, Hautboi, ou avec l'Accompagnement de Deux Violons, Taille, & Basse deux Cors de Chasse a Libitum Composées par J. C. Fischer. Chéz Hummel, á Berlin avec Privilege du Roi; á Amsterdam au Grand Magazin de Musique et aux Adresses ordinairs [n.d.].
  - Several loose printed sheets, some unidentifiable., Small double-sided sheet cut from page, with treble melodies numbered sequentially. (Box-folder 3:13)
    235: I'd Be a Butterfly by T. Bayley
    236: Let Us Haste to Kelvin Grove by C. E. Horn
    237: The Plain Gold Ring by Weber
    238: Buy a Broom, Germany
    Overture to The Deserter. For solo keyboard.
    12 pages of unidentifiable sheets for solo keyboard
  - Bound volume, with green cover., Inscribed on cover: Mademoiselle Jefferson, L'Abbaye Royale de Panthemont Paris. (Box-folder 3:14)
    Pieces de Clavecin Primier Livre dédié a Madame de Caze Trésorier générale des Postes, et relais de France et fermie e générale par Mr. Balbastre Organiste de l'Eglise Paroissiale de St Roch, due Concert Spirituel et Maitre de Clavecin de L'Abbaie Roialle de Panthemont [Paris, ca. 1765]. Includes:
    Overture: La De Caze
    La D'héricour
    La Ségur
    La Monmartel ou la brunoy
    La Boullogne
    La Castelmore
    La Courteille
    La Bellaud
    La Landmarck
    La Berville
    La Lugeac
    La Suzanne
    La Genty
    La Malesherbe
    La Berryer ou la Lamoignon
    La Laporte
    La Morisseau
    Trois Quatuors de Mr. Ignace Pleyel, tires de l'Oeuvre dédié a Sa M. le Roi de Prusse, Arrangés pour Clavecin ou Piano-Forte avec Accompagnement de Violon et Basse par Mr. Lachnitt. Printed Chez Imbault, Md. De Musique au Mont d'or rue St. Honoré entre la rue des Poulies et l'h?tel d'Aligre, No. 627 [Paris, ca. 1785].
    Trois Sonates pour le Clavecin ou le Forte-Piano avec Violon ad Libitum dediees a son altesse Serenisime Madame la Princesse Regnante de Liechtenstein par L. Kozeluch. Chez Mr. Boyer, rue de Richelieu á la Clef d'Or, passage du Caffé de foy [Paris, ca. 1788].
    Trois Sonates pour Clavecin ou Forte Piano avec Violon et Violoncelle Composés Par Mr. J. S. Schroetter Oeuvre VIII. Chez le Sr. Seiber Musicien rue St. Honore entre celle des Vielles Etuve et celles D'orleans chez l'Apothicaire No. 92 [Paris, ca. 1785]. Prix: 7.4
    A Duett for two Performers on One Forte Piano by Sig. Clementi, op. VI. Printed by J. Dale. No. 132 Oxford Street [London, ca. 1786]. Price: 2s: 6d.
  - Bound volume, with green hardcover., Inscribed: "Mrs. Randolph Monticello Virginia." (Box-folder 4:15)
    Printed music for solo keyboard instrument. Contains:
    Six Sonatas pour le Clavecin ou le Piano Forte composée par Jean Cretien Bach Martre de Musique de S.M. la Reine D'angleterre, Oeuvre V, Gravée par Mlle. Vend?me et le Sr. Moria. Published Chez Mr. Le Due Rue Traversiere St. Honore á cte de l'Hotel de Bayonne, Paris [ca. 1780]. Price: 9tt.
    La Chasse pour le Clavecin ou Forte-piano par Muzio Clementi, Oeuvre XVI. Printed and sold by Longman and Broderip No. 26 Cheapside and No. 13 Hay Market, London [ca. 1786]. Price: 3s.
    Trio pour le Clavecin ou Piano-Forte avec Accompagnement de Violon or Clarinette et Alto par W[olfgang] A[madeus] Mozart, Ouevre 16. Published Chez Lr Duc, Successeur de Mr. de la Chevardiere, Rue du Roule á la Croix d'Or, Paris [ca. 1775]. Price: 3tt.
  - String bound collection of manuscript paper. (Box-folder 4:16)
    Includes variations, songs, waltzes, melodies from operas, tables of note values and rests, and miscellaneous unidentifiable pieces, in several different handwritings. Identified pieces include:
    Gathering of the Clans
    Andante con. Var. Pleyel
    Air by Mazzinghi
    Timour the Tartar
    Handel's Water Piece
    Overture de Blaise et Babet
    Musette d'Armide
    Overture de la Caravane
    Pleyel's German Hymn
    Anthem for Funerals
    Twilight Dews
    The Plighted Vow
    The Harp that once thro Sara's Halls
    When he who Adores Thee
    The Time I've Lost in Wrong
    The Romaika
    Alice Gray
    A Favorite Waltz
    The Warrenton Waltz
    Neapolitan Waltz
    Swiss Waltz
    The College Hornpipe
    Fisher's Hornpipe
    Bring Flowers
    Hurrah for the Bonnets of Blue
    Bavarian Air
  - Unidentifiable printed scraps and fragments, including six sonatas for solo keyboard instrument. (Box-folder 4:17)
    Photocopied title page has been added from the Library of Congress copy of the score by RK, suggesting that this collection is:
    Sei Sonate a Violino Solo e Basso Dedicate Alla Sacra Real Maesta di Carlo Emanuele Re Di Sardegna by Da Gaetano Pugnani, Opera III. Published Chez M. de la Chevardiere, rue du Roule á la Croix d'Or, Paris [1760].
  - (Box-folder 4:18)
    Trois Quatuors de Mr. Ignace Pleyel tires de l'Oeuvre dédié á Sa M. le (?) Pruffe, Arrangé pour Clavecin ou Piano-Forte avec accompagnement de Violon by [Ludwig Wenzil] Lachn[itth]. Published Paris, [ca. 1788]. Cover page of this document is very worn and not all printing is legible. Printed sheet music.
  - (Box-folder 4:19)
    Ouverture de la Bonne Fille Arrangée Pour le Clavecin ou le Forte Piano avec Accompagnement de Violon par L. F. Despreaux, Maitre de Clavecin. Published Chez Mr. Boyer au Magazin de Musique, Rue neuve des petits Champs, près la Rue neuve St. Roch, Maison de Mr. Lauron Apoticaire, No. 83, Paris [ca. 1785].
  - (Box-folder 4:20)
    A group of selections from some operas popular in Paris during the Jeffersons' stay there: Le Carillon des Trois Fermiers, Trio d'Azor, Air des Trois Fermiers, Rose Chérie de Zemire et Azor, Air de Trois Fermiers. There are notes and lyrics throughout the pieces in the handwriting of Martha Jefferson (Randolph). Printed sheet music for solo keyboard instrument. No cover page to indicate publication information.
  - (Box-folder 4:21)